Every one of you left something behind
to stand here.
A field, a family, a quiet life.
But you know why we're here.
I don't need to say it.
You carry it in your chests.
Every one of you.
>> [clears throat]
>> Yeah, hi.
Sorry if this was covered earlier, my
lord, but
why are we actually here?
>> Yeah.
Why are we here?
>> Are you even working?
>> Uh yes.
>> So this is what working looks like?
>> Oh, I'm sorry, my lord. Please tell me
how to write a movie since, you know,
you've written so many of them.
>> Hey everyone, Ian here from the Runway
creative team, and today I'm going to
show you exactly how to make that
medieval comedy scene that you just
watched inside of Runway. We're also
going to make some additional scenes,
and of course throw in some tips and
tricks. Making a short film like this is
obviously a really great way to practice
your creative skills using AI tools, but
what's even more important is practicing
and honing your skills as a storyteller.
So we're going to cover some of that,
too. So let's jump straight into this
first scene that you saw, and I'll show
you how we built all the pieces, and
then how we put them together.
>> [music]
>> First, we'll start with the Runway MCP
to help us build out our character. And
at this point, I don't really have a
specific look in mind for him, so I'm
going to keep the prompt very general
and just see what the model comes up
with. Sometimes you don't really know
what you want until you see it, and so
this is just a really great way to
brainstorm and get some inspiration.
Also, we're going to run this prompt in
both Nano Banana and GPT-2 since
different image models give you
different results, and sometimes you
don't really know which one's going to
give you a better result until you try
it.
And as you can see, GPT gave us a
character that looks very much like a
model, while Nano Banana gives us a
slightly more natural face.
But even still, all of these look a
little too serious, and because we know
that this is going to be a comedic
piece, we maybe want somebody who fits
the genre a little bit better. So
instead of trying to describe that look,
we'll just simply ask Claude exactly
what we want. This is a step in the
right direction, but it might be a
little bit too far. But, the great thing
about using the Runway MCP here is that
Claude has a historical context of
everything that you've asked inside of
the chat. So, you don't necessarily need
to know or worry about the prompts
specifically. You can just talk to it in
plain language and kind of iterate on
the go. So, we'll continue working with
Claude asking for variations in
ethnicity, hair, and other traits until
we land on a character that we like.
>> [music]
>> And then we'll do the same thing for our
screenwriter character and for the
soldier in the scene.
And now we're ready to move on to the
location.
So, for the first location, I don't
really know what I want it to look like,
but I do know what I want it to feel
like. Desaturated colors, kind of gray
and dreary, somber tones. So, of course
we can go in and describe all of that
with words, but in my opinion, a faster
way would be to use a reference image to
help us get there a little bit quicker.
And just a quick pro tip about using a
reference image, don't use a reference
image of the exact thing that you're
trying to create because the image model
is going to want to just recreate that
thing one to one. So, in this example,
I'm not going to use a reference image
of a castle, I'm going to use a
reference image of the vibe I'm going
for. This image is in the same world,
but it's completely different from the
scene that I'm making.
Before we bring in our character, it's
important to kind of set the scene and
the tone and orient the viewer as to
where we are in this world. And because
we're going to have this hard turn to
comedy later, we want to create contrast
by having the beginning feel the
opposite of that, very serious, very
somber, and very ominous.
But, what if we don't know exactly what
shots we want to use or we want to be
able to explore other options? Well, I'm
here to show you a brainstorming tip on
how to do exactly that. I'm going to
take our hero image and create a
5-second seed dance generation from it
asking for 20 unique angles, inserts,
and details from the scene.
Now, I of course could ask for something
specific like all wide shots or all
soldier inserts, but in this case I
actually just want to let the model do
its thing and let it kind of dream it up
on its own. And what we get back is this
clip of a bunch of short shots that
aren't usable in this state, but that's
okay cuz we're just going to be looking
for images that we like that we can then
extract and build a video clip out of or
just simply use it as inspiration.
Here, for example, I love this image of
the soldiers as well as the torch. The
problem with the soldiers is that they
all have the same face and I don't
really love the composition of this
torch shot.
And we're not necessarily going to use
these exact frames one-to-one, but these
are shots specifically that I didn't
have in mind before, but now I do.
And like before, we're going to use our
hero shot as a reference in C Dance and
prompt for four individual shots in the
same generation by describing each shot
in very simple terms: shot type, camera
position and movement, and action.
Sometimes it helps to have very detailed
prompts, while other times you can just
put in a few keywords like cinematic or
shallow depth of field and let the model
fill in the blanks. For example, the
prompt for this shot of the torch was
simply close-up of a burning torch.
On the other hand, the prompt for this
shot of the hooves was tracking shot,
profile side view following a black
horse's hooves slowly walking through
the mud, legs of soldiers out of focus
in the foreground, other soldiers' legs
in the background out of focus.
And as you can see, we are only
describing the most relevant visual
components of the scene. You don't
necessarily need to say that the horse
is churning up mud with every step or
walking exactly 2.5 mph. Walking slowly
through the mud, that's it. You are
giving simple instructions so that the
model understands what you are trying to
go for creatively. And now that we've
set the scene, it is time to bring in
our character.
Ideally, we would have our character in
our hero shot, but we purposely left him
out of this because we thought it would
be a little bit too complicated to get
him and the castle and the soldiers and
the environment all like perfect in the
composition. So, instead, we're going to
be bringing him in by using the
character reference image that we
already created as well as our hero
shot.
And right away, I realized our mistake,
no helmet. This is not how a knight
that's going into battle looks.
Now, we could, of course, prompt C Dance
to just add a helmet to our character,
but that's not going to scale across the
entirety of a short film. We need the
exact helmet to be the same helmet every
single time. So, instead, we're going to
fix the problem on the image level and
create a version of him with a helmet.
And this is what you're going to want to
do every single time you have a
character that has unique attributes
about them, a specific outfit, a
specific item that they're holding, a
specific scar on their face, you're
going to want to fix this at the image
reference level. That way, every time
you go to create a scene with that
character, it's going to match
one-to-one.
And now, with the new reference, we're
going to bring him in again with a very
simple prompt.
And this is what we're looking for right
here, a new hero shot.
Because our character isn't in the
original hero image, it's going to be
next to impossible to recreate how he
enters the scene every time from
generation to generation.
Sometimes the castle might be behind
him, sometimes it won't. Sometimes the
soldiers in the background will be
facing him, other times they'll have
their backs to him. So, to keep the
generations as consistent as possible,
we're going to use this frame in
combination with our hero shot for every
generation pretty much from here on out.
So, now let's talk about how we're going
to bring in one of the other characters
into this scene, the soldier, and show
you some of the problems that we ran
into and how we got around them.
Originally, we tried to bring in the
soldier just like we brought in the
knight. Hero shot plus the character
references, but the issue was that the
soldier didn't look like he was part of
the other troops.
He was too small or had different
lighting than the rest.
So, our idea was to fix it on the image
level and create a frame of him in the
ranks, but instantly got results like
these. Now, we could have taken the
time, reworked the prompt, and
eventually gotten there, but we realized
that it didn't really matter what he
looked like, and so instead of fighting
the model over and over again, we just
kind of leaned into the limitations and
didn't really care what he looked like.
And a few generations later, we ended up
with this shot and now we could use that
frame as a reference image to keep all
future takes consistent.
>> Actually, why are we here?
>> When writing prompts that contain
dialogue, you are essentially directing
a performance. You can use ellipses,
those three little dots when you write a
sentence, to create natural breaks in
the dialogue.
>> Uh
Yeah, sorry, my lord.
>> Or you can add scene direction right in
the middle of lines.
>> Sorry, my lord.
>> [snorts]
>> But why are we actually here?
>> Sometimes just a word or two can reshape
a performance.
>> Why are we actually here?
>> The other thing you can experiment with
is the length of the output clip itself
because the model is going to try to
cram in and fit in everything that you
ask it into that amount of time, whether
it's a short clip or a super long clip.
>> Yeah, sorry, my lord, but
why are we actually here?
>> Yeah, sorry, my lord.
Uh
But why are we actually here?
>> So, if a scene is feeling really rushed,
try lengthening the clip. And if the
scene is feeling really dull and
lifeless, try shortening the clip.
That's going to help your performances a
lot.
And before we continue talking about all
the technical stuff, let's pause for a
moment and let's talk about the story
and how you can use AI to develop your
story and get better at storytelling.
The key to every story, every scene, is
conflict. And the easiest way to create
conflict is to take your character and
put them in a scene with somebody that
believes the exact opposite of what they
do. Like our knight and our
screenwriter.
Two friends catching up over lunch is a
conversation, but two friends arguing
about who should pick up the check,
that's a scene. But what's equally
important is the why. Why does the
character want this?
>> I've got a good idea of why we're here.
>> Is it to rescue a princess?
>> a princess!
>> Fine, whatever. And why do you love this
princess so much?
>> Because she's beautiful, of course.
>> Someone kill me.
>> If it's not important to the character,
or it's too basic or shallow, it's not
going to resonate with the audience and
they also won't care about the thing.
So, let's jump back into Claude using
the MCP and let's figure out where our
story goes next. In this case, I want to
create a scene where our knight first
meets the princess, while at the same
time keeping the bickering dynamic
between him and the writer.
What's great about working in NCP is
that Claude already has context for this
film and if we wanted to, we could feed
it any number of assets to use. However,
in this case, we'll keep it simple and
ask for a handful of ideas for a scene
where the knight first meets the
princess. And after some back and forth,
we land on the idea that he first meets
her after winning a jousting tournament.
>> [music]
>> Now, this I like. So, what happens next?
>> Well, you get to know her as a person
and really fall in love with her.
>> Right. Yeah, not going to lie, that
sounds super boring. Besides, I already
know plenty about her.
>> Name one thing and don't say beautiful.
>> She has hair.
>> [sighs]
>> Which is lovely and I bet smells great.
That's three things right there. I think
I win your little battle of wits.
You're writing all of this down, right?
>> Absolutely not.
>> One thing that I want to address in that
scene is the hero image, which was this.
In this instance, the writer character
is not present at the start of the
scene, but we still created a hero image
with her in it because we could use it
for every other shot except for the
first one.
And for the first shot, it was as simple
as creating a new hero image by taking
her out of the frame.
Remember, it's always easier to remove
something from a scene rather than add
it back in, which is the problem that we
had earlier with our soldier. So, when
you're creating your image for your
scene, try to pick a point in the scene
where all the characters are visible in
the scene at the same time if you can.
Okay, now let's talk about audio, how
you can keep it consistent, and also how
you can use it to shape your
performance.
>> You should go.
>> I'm not leaving you.
>> I'm afraid
I'm the one
that's going to have to leave you.
>> No, because you're going [music] to
fight.
You've never once done the easy thing.
Don't start now.
>> Loving you is the easy thing.
The only easy thing I ever did.
>> [sighs]
[laughter]
>> So, quick thought.
>> Oh my god.
>> Uh what if Oh, this is a good idea.
You're going to like this. What if I
you know
didn't die? How cool would that be?
>> It's poetic.
>> Right, yeah, sure. Love that bit, but
what if Oh, oh, someone
else died?
>> Like who?
>> Oh, I don't know.
Could be anyone, really.
>> I will kill you myself.
>> Now, usually if you use the exact same
images in the exact same scene with the
exact same descriptions, and you're just
kind of creating in that pattern, you
will more or less get the exact same
character voices within that scene.
>> What if I decapitated someone to impress
her?
Maybe that old woman right there. What
if I decapitated someone to impress her?
Maybe that old woman right there.
>> But, if you decide to change any one of
those things, like the location for
example, your character voice might
drift, and that's something that you
don't want to deal with. So, here are
some tips and tricks that you can use to
get the same consistent character voice
across all your scenes, no matter what.
The easiest is to upload a short audio
clip of your character talking from the
previous scene, and then use that as a
voice reference.
Another way is you could use a video
from a previous generation as a
reference. This is great in cases where
you have multiple characters, and having
a visual and audio reference helps to
keep the model from getting confused as
to which voice belongs to which
character, which can happen especially
if the characters look similar or sound
similar.
Additionally, you can create a character
reference video, where instead of using
a still image, you actually have a video
of your character speaking directly to
camera.
>> I am the night.
And this is what my voice sounds like.
>> And finally, you can use the audio
itself to drive the performance.
Meaning, you take the audio from a
generation or several that you've edited
together, upload it as a reference, and
tell the model to lip-sync the scene to
the audio.
And this is a way to get more consistent
performances out of these models,
because the characters in your scene are
going to deliver the same lines the same
way every single time, so it's a little
bit more predictable. Here's an example
where we took individual lines from
several different generations, cut them
together, and then used it to drive the
performances.
>> My father beheaded three men at his
wedding. My mother talks about it every
year.
They were very happy. My father beheaded
three men at his wedding.
My mother talks about it every year.
They were very happy. My father beheaded
three men at his wedding. My mother
talks about it every year.
They were very happy.
>> So, these are just some of the ways that
you can use these tools to your
advantage to be a little bit more
precise and intentional with the content
that you're trying to create inside of
Runway. And you might be doing a
medieval comedy piece, or you might be
doing something completely different.
But knowing how to use these tools is
super important, and they are just
tools. Prompts will only get you so far.
The more important thing to focus on and
to really hone in on is your vision,
your voice, and the story that you want
to tell. And these tools are only going
to help you tell that story even better,
even faster, and with even more pizzazz.
Anyways, thank you so much for watching
this video. My name is Ian from the
Runway creative team. If you want to see
more videos like this, more long-form
tutorials where we teach you about
storytelling and using AI tools, make
sure you drop a comment in the comment
section below, and subscribe to the
Runway YouTube channel so you don't miss
out on any videos in the future.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Hey.